http://www.askdavetaylor.com/privacy-policy/

HomePrivacy Policy
The policy: This privacy policy notice is for this website, AskDaveTaylor.com and served by Intuitive Systems, LLC, Postal Box 1315, Boulder CO 80306 and governs the privacy of those who use it. The purpose of this policy is to explain to you how we control, process, handle and protect your personal information while browsing or using this website, including your rights under current laws and regulations. If you do not agree to the following policy you should cease viewing / using this website.
Policy key definitions:
“I”, “our”, “us”, or “we” refer to the business, AskDaveTaylor.com.
“you”, “the user” refer to the person(s) using this website.
GDPR means General Data Protection Act.
PECR means Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulation.
ICO means Information Commissioner’s Office.
Cookies mean small files stored on a users computer or device.
Processing of your personal data
Under the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) we control and / or process any personal information about you electronically using the following lawful bases.
We are exempt from registration in the ICO Data Protection Register because you grant us Consent based on this document detailing your privacy rights and our use of your data. Please note that we do not retain your visit information but we do retain any comments left on the site in perpetuity.
If, as determined by us, the lawful basis upon which we process your personal information changes, we will endeavor to notify you about the change and any new lawful basis to be used if required. We shall stop processing your personal information if the lawful basis used is no longer relevant.
Your individual rights
Under the GDPR your rights are as follows. You can read more about your rights in details here;
the right to be informed;
the right of access;
the right to rectification;
the right to erasure;
the right to restrict processing;
the right to data portability;
the right to object; and
the right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling.
You also have the right to complain to the ICO  if you feel there is a problem with the way we are handling your data.
We handle subject access requests in accordance with the GDPR.
Internet cookies
We use cookies on this website to provide you with a better user experience. We do this by placing a small text file on your device / computer hard drive to track how you use the website, to record or log whether you have seen particular messages that we display, to keep you logged into the website where applicable, to display relevant adverts or content, referred you to a third party website.
Some cookies are required to enjoy and use the full functionality of this website.
We use a cookie control system which allows you to accept the use of cookies, and control which cookies are saved to your device / computer. Some cookies will be saved for specific time periods, where others may last indefinitely. Your web browser should provide you with the controls to manage and delete cookies from your device, please see your web browser options.
In addition, advertisers that we work with also use cookies in a similar manner: If you would prefer to opt out then it’s recommended that you consider an ad blocker or disable cookies within your Web browser.
Data security and protection
We ensure the security of any personal information we hold by using secure data storage technologies and precise procedures in how we store, access and manage that information. Our methods meet the GDPR compliance requirement.
Transparent Privacy Explanations
We have provided some further explanations about user privacy and the way we use this website to help promote a transparent and honest user privacy methodology.
Sponsored links, affiliate tracking & commissions
Our website also contains adverts, sponsored and affiliate links on some pages. These are typically served through our advertising partners; Google Adsense, eBay Partner Network, Amazon Affiliates, or similar. We only use trusted advertising partners who each have high standards of user privacy and security. However we do not control the actual adverts seen / displayed by our advertising partners.
Clicking on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links may track your actions by using a cookie saved to your device. You can read more about cookies on this website above. Your actions are usually recorded as a referral from our website by this cookie. In most cases we earn a very small commission from the advertiser or advertising partner, at no cost to you, whether you make a purchase on their website or not.
We use advertising partners in these ways to help generate an income from the website, which allows us to continue our work and provide you with the best overall experience and valued information.
If you have any concerns about this we suggest you do not click on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links found throughout the website.
Email marketing messages & subscription
Under the GDPR we use the consent lawful basis for anyone subscribing to our newsletter or marketing mailing list. We only collect certain data about you, as detailed in the “Processing of your personal date” above. Any email marketing messages we send are done so through an EMS, email marketing service provider. An EMS is a third party service provider of software / applications that allows marketers to send out email marketing campaigns to a list of users.
Email marketing messages that we send may contain tracking beacons / tracked clickable links or similar server technologies in order to track subscriber activity within email marketing messages. Where used, such marketing messages may record a range of data such as; times, dates, I.P addresses, opens, clicks, forwards, geographic and demographic data. Such data, within its limitations will show the activity each subscriber made for that email campaign.
Any email marketing messages we send are in accordance with the GDPR and the PECR. We provide you with an easy method to withdraw your consent (unsubscribe) or manage your preferences / the information we hold about you at any time. See any marketing messages for instructions on how to unsubscribe or manage your preferences, you can also unsubscribe from our mailing list at Feedblitz.com, by following this link, otherwise contact the EMS provider.
Our EMS provider is Feedblitz.com. We hold the following information about you within our EMS system;
More information about the Feedblitz can be found here: Privacy Statement and Personal Cookie Settings.
What Are All The Different Audio & Video File Formats?
My PC Mouse Barely Moves My Cursor! How Can I Fix It?
What’s The Trick for Renaming an Amazon Alexa (Echo)?
Easiest Way to Have an Automatic Signature In Email?
How Can I Pre-Assign Zoom Breakout Rooms for my Students?
report this ad
On Our YouTube ChannelLucyd Lyte vs Bose Frames Tenor - Bluetooth Sunglasses - COMPARISON & REVIEWRoccat Burst Pro Gamer PC Mouse -- REVIEWCategories
AdSense, AdWords and PPC Help (106)
Amazon Echo & Kindle Help (78)
Amazon, eBay and Online Shopping Help (157)
Android Help (156)
Apple Watch Help (49)
Articles, Tutorials and Reviews (325)
Business Advice (190)
Computer and Internet Basics (712)
d) None of the Above (160)
Facebook Help (360)
Google & Gmail Help (151)
HTML and Web Design (243)
Instagram Help (42)
iPad Help (135)
iPhone Help (566)
LinkedIn Help (79)
Linux Help (146)
Linux Shell Script Programming (86)
Mac & MacOS Help (824)
Most Popular (10)
MP3 Player Help (181)
Outlook & Office 365 Help (7)
Pinterest Help (53)
Reddit Help (11)
SEO & Marketing (79)
Spam, Scams & Security (81)
Trade Show Updates (23)
Twitter Help (211)
Video Game Tips (66)
Web Site Traffic Tips (62)
Windows 10 Help (817)
Wordpress Help (201)
Writing and Publishing (72)
report this ad
YouTube Help (43)
YouTube Video Reviews (159)
Zoom, Skype & Video Chat Help (39)
Archives Archives
Select Month
December 2020  (8)
November 2020  (25)
October 2020  (24)
September 2020  (26)
August 2020  (27)
July 2020  (26)
June 2020  (25)
May 2020  (26)
April 2020  (26)
March 2020  (26)
February 2020  (21)
January 2020  (26)
December 2019  (25)
November 2019  (25)
October 2019  (26)
September 2019  (25)
August 2019  (29)
July 2019  (28)
June 2019  (28)
May 2019  (26)
April 2019  (25)
March 2019  (28)
February 2019  (24)
January 2019  (30)
December 2018  (27)
November 2018  (27)
October 2018  (28)
September 2018  (28)
August 2018  (25)
July 2018  (25)
June 2018  (25)
May 2018  (26)
April 2018  (25)
March 2018  (28)
February 2018  (28)
January 2018  (26)
December 2017  (26)
November 2017  (27)
October 2017  (25)
September 2017  (28)
August 2017  (29)
July 2017  (29)
June 2017  (27)
May 2017  (28)
April 2017  (26)
March 2017  (27)
February 2017  (22)
January 2017  (25)
December 2016  (25)
November 2016  (24)
October 2016  (26)
September 2016  (30)
August 2016  (33)
July 2016  (29)
June 2016  (25)
May 2016  (27)
April 2016  (30)
March 2016  (30)
February 2016  (31)
January 2016  (32)
December 2015  (23)
November 2015  (30)
October 2015  (27)
September 2015  (27)
August 2015  (26)
July 2015  (27)
June 2015  (25)
May 2015  (22)
April 2015  (26)
March 2015  (26)
February 2015  (26)
January 2015  (24)
December 2014  (20)
November 2014  (20)
October 2014  (28)
September 2014  (21)
August 2014  (24)
July 2014  (19)
June 2014  (24)
May 2014  (24)
April 2014  (22)
March 2014  (23)
February 2014  (23)
January 2014  (20)
December 2013  (26)
November 2013  (22)
October 2013  (25)
September 2013  (25)
August 2013  (20)
July 2013  (27)
June 2013  (21)
May 2013  (22)
April 2013  (28)
March 2013  (27)
February 2013  (28)
January 2013  (31)
December 2012  (28)
November 2012  (27)
October 2012  (27)
September 2012  (26)
August 2012  (28)
July 2012  (24)
June 2012  (29)
May 2012  (30)
April 2012  (28)
March 2012  (29)
February 2012  (29)
January 2012  (27)
December 2011  (25)
November 2011  (27)
October 2011  (22)
September 2011  (31)
August 2011  (23)
July 2011  (21)
June 2011  (27)
May 2011  (26)
April 2011  (25)
March 2011  (29)
February 2011  (26)
January 2011  (30)
December 2010  (31)
November 2010  (26)
October 2010  (26)
September 2010  (27)
August 2010  (27)
July 2010  (27)
June 2010  (27)
May 2010  (25)
April 2010  (29)
March 2010  (26)
February 2010  (26)
January 2010  (30)
December 2009  (36)
November 2009  (27)
October 2009  (28)
September 2009  (24)
August 2009  (30)
July 2009  (27)
June 2009  (26)
May 2009  (26)
April 2009  (30)
March 2009  (29)
February 2009  (23)
January 2009  (32)
December 2008  (33)
November 2008  (26)
October 2008  (30)
September 2008  (29)
August 2008  (26)
July 2008  (28)
June 2008  (27)
May 2008  (22)
April 2008  (27)
March 2008  (26)
February 2008  (25)
January 2008  (28)
December 2007  (35)
November 2007  (26)
October 2007  (25)
September 2007  (23)
August 2007  (27)
July 2007  (28)
June 2007  (25)
May 2007  (33)
April 2007  (29)
March 2007  (32)
February 2007  (26)
January 2007  (29)
December 2006  (31)
November 2006  (33)
October 2006  (44)
September 2006  (48)
August 2006  (53)
July 2006  (31)
June 2006  (37)
May 2006  (43)
April 2006  (44)
March 2006  (56)
February 2006  (71)
January 2006  (51)
December 2005  (43)
November 2005  (43)
October 2005  (41)
September 2005  (46)
August 2005  (65)
July 2005  (43)
June 2005  (34)
May 2005  (38)
April 2005  (37)
March 2005  (37)
February 2005  (28)
January 2005  (39)
December 2004  (50)
November 2004  (35)
October 2004  (8)
September 2004  (8)
August 2004  (6)
July 2004  (5)
June 2004  (12)
May 2004  (18)
April 2004  (5)
March 2004  (4)
February 2004  (9)
January 2004  (9)
December 2003  (4)
November 2003  (2)
October 2003  (2)
September 2003  (1)
August 2003  (4)
July 2003  (2)
June 2003  (5)
May 2003  (3)
April 2003  (3)
